Rahmanda Wibowo

Email: rahmandawibowo@gmail.com

Github: github.com/rahmanda

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/rahmandawibowo

Personal

I have years of experience working professionally as a front-end web developer with a big e-commerce company and digital transformation organisation. I have sharpened my skills on the technical side, built an effective collaboration with many different functions and stakeholders, and created a community for engineers in the organisation. I love everything related to continuous learning, collaborative working and getting insights from data.

Experience

Front-End Engineer, GovTech Edu

May 2021 - present

GovTech Edu is a non-profit tech organisation, partnering with the Ministry of Education to build a high quality government education platform in Indonesia. As a lead front-end engineer, I contribute to develop multiple progressive web apps from zero to production, maintain the web server up and running, develop various productivity tools for front-end engineers, actively participate in many technical discussions with stakeholders, and provide troubleshooting and consultancy for web related problems across teams. I also co-founded a regular internal event called We Talk Frontend!: a knowledge sharing forum for frontend engineers in the organisation.

Full Stack Developer, AdaKerja

Dec 2020 - Feb 2021

AdaKerja is a job marketplace and payroll management system for blue collar workers. During my tenure as a full stack developer, I developed multiple web apps and backend APIs using Javascript and Node.js, worked with external partners to integrate a third party analytic tool, and gave reports and technical insights to stakeholders.

Senior Front-End Engineer, Bukalapak

Oct 2015 - Nov 2020

Bukalapak is one of the first and the largest online marketplace in Indonesia. My responsibilities included: built and maintained multiple digital product apps, worked closely with back-end engineers and QA testers, communicated requirements with UI designers, collaborated with engineers within and across teams, and gave technical insights to product managers. I also worked to improve developer productivity by producing multiple UI tools.

Education

Master of Statistics and Data Science, Hasselt University

2021 - present

Core Subjects: Probability and Statistics, Data Management, Generalised Linear Model, Advanced Python, Data Visualisation, Machine Learning, Neural Networks and Deep Learning

Bachelor of Computer Science, IPB University (Indonesia)

2011 - 2015

Core Subjects: Software Engineering, Information System, Information Retrieval, Operations Research, Computer and Network Systems, Data Mining

Technical Skills

Languages

Javascript/Typescript, Python, R, Ruby, SQL, HTML/CSS

Tools and frameworks

Javascript frameworks (Vue.js, React, Svelte), D3.js, Sentry, Linux, CI/CD (Github, Gitlab), Docker, Prometheus and Grafana, Big Query and Data Studio, Google Cloud Platform

Side Projects

Nusadata – Data Visualisation Website (http://www.nusadata.org)

Collections of data visualisation based on Indonesian statistics using D3.js.

Ambercat – NPM package (http://github.com/rahmanda/ambercat)

Simple static blog generator based on Vue.js client and server-side rendering capability. It makes building a blog from scratch easier and customising the blog theme with less configuration. It also supports localization out of the box.

Tailwind SCSS – CSS Library (https://github.com/rahmanda/tailwindscss)

SCSS version of Tailwind CSS, a utility-based CSS framework. It enables people who can't use modern module bundlers such as Webpack and Rollup on their legacy app to use the framework. This library is made as close as possible with current features of Tailwind CSS.